hugo.com 2014-02-09

# P&G Privacy Statement

P&G Consumer Privacy Statement

Thank you for visiting Procter & Gamble (P&G).

Three billion times a day, P&G brands touch the lives of people around the world. Our corporate tradition is rooted in the principles of personal integrity, respect for the individual, and doing what's right for the long-term.

Trust is a cornerstone of our corporate mission. P&G is committed to maintaining your trust by protecting personal information we collect about you.

This Global Privacy Statement (Privacy Statement) describes the information that P&G (The Procter & Gamble Company and its affiliated companies and subsidiaries) collects about you; how we use and protect this information; and the choices you can make about how we use this information.

Back to top

  * The European Union Data Protection Directive and the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. P&G adheres to the Safe Harbor Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.
  * Fair information practices established by the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD).
  * The Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation forum (APEC) Privacy Framework.
  * Applicable country, national, state and local data protection laws.
  * Some country laws require country specific information in a privacy statement. Please click to read that information for those countries.  
**Argentina** **Belgium** **Canada** **France** **Greece** **Korea** **Italy** **Mexico** **The Netherlands** **Portugal** **Spain**  

Back to top

This Privacy Statement applies to information, including personal information, collected about you by P&G. 

Personal information is information, or a combination of pieces of information that could reasonably allow you to be identified. 

Some P&G programs may contain links to non-P&G sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of those sites. We recommend you review the privacy policies of each site you visit.

Back to top

We may collect information about you from a variety of sources, including information we collect from you directly; information we collect about you when you visit our sites, use our services, or view our online advertisements; and information we collect about you from other sources (where permitted by law).

_**Information we collect directly from you:**_  
We collect information directly from you when you choose to participate in our offers and programs or otherwise provide information directly to us. The following are examples of information we may collect directly from you:

  * Name, email address, postal address.
  * Username and password.
  * Phone number or mobile number.
  * Age.
  * Date of birth.
  * Other information about you and your family such as gender or product use preferences and/or behaviors.
  * Biometrics collected during volunteer consumer research studies (such as facial expression recognition, heart rate, and skin condition)
  * Demographic information.
  * Payment information (such as a credit card).
  * Future communication preferences
  * Contact information for friends you may wish us to contact. When you provide us information for these refer a friend messages, we use the information only to send the message you request.

_**Information we collect when you visit our sites, use our services, or view our online advertisements:**_

We use cookies and other technologies to collect information about you when you visit our sites, use our services, or view online advertisements. The following are examples of information we may collect with these technologies:

  * Your browser type and operating system.
  * Web pages you view.
  * Links you click.
  * IP address.
  * Site you visited before coming to our site.
  * P&G emails you open and/or forward
  * P&G offers or links you connect to via emails.

_**Information we collect from other sources:**_

We may obtain information about you from other sources, including commercially available sources, such as data aggregators and public databases. The following are examples of information we may collect from other sources.

  * Name, postal address.
  * Age.
  * Income level.
  * Marital status and number of children.
  * Your interests such as hobbies and pets.
  * Consumer and market research data.
  * Purchase behavior.
  * Publicly observed data or activities, such as blogs, videos, internet postings, user generated content, and in-store shopping behavior.

**All of the information we collect about you may be combined to help us tailor our communications to you and to develop world-class products and services of superior quality.**

Back to top

**To provide offers, products and services.** We use the information we collect to provide the products and services you request, to tell you about other products and services offered by P&G, and to manage our sites and services.

The following are ways we may use the information we collect about you:

  * Send samples, premiums, products and information.
  * Develop new products and services.
  * Enroll you in contests, programs, or offers you request.
  * To provide you with other services that we have offered to you
  * Create and manage your account.
  * Process payment for purchases or other services.
  * Protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions.
  * Where permitted by law, provide you with customized, unsolicited offers and information about P&G’s products and services through postal mail.
  * Develop and provide advertising tailored to your interests.
  * Analyze the use of our products, services, and sites.
  * Understand how you arrived at our site.
  * Determine the effectiveness of our advertising.
  * Enforce our Terms and Conditions and otherwise manage our business.

Back to top

_**Choices**_  
We give you choices about how we communicate with you. _Digital / Electronic Communications_ (examples: email, mobile).  
We only send you promotional mobile or email messages if you explicitly ask to receive these. (You opt in).  
You can stop receiving promotional mobile and email messages from a particular P&G brand or group by following the instructions provided in any such message you receive from that brand or group.

 _Postal Mail_

Where permitted by law, we may mail you unsolicited offers or product information that we believe is of interest to you.

You can stop receiving promotional postal mail from a particular P&G brand or group. Promotional postal mail may contain opt out instructions, and you can stop receiving promotional postal mail from a particular P&G brand or group (such as Every Day Solutions, Envie de Plus, Zin in Meer) by following those instructions.

You can also stop receiving promotional email or postal communication from a particular P&G brand or group through this Privacy Statement. Please [click here](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/contact_us/privacy-central-contact-interactive.html "click here") to select your country and learn how to complete your request.

**PLEASE NOTE:** If you choose to stop receiving promotional messages from us, we will honor your request. However, we will continue to send you service related communications and we may need to keep the information we have collected about you for record keeping, analysis or other reasons, to the extent permitted by law.

**_Access_**  
We take steps to keep your personal information accurate. You can view, correct or update the personal contact information you provide P&G. Some P&G programs provide access to view or update personal information online. Check where you registered to learn if you can view or update your information there.

If information access and update is not available where you registered, [click here](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/privacy_country_list.html) to select your country and learn how to access and update the personal information you provided P&G. P&G does not charge for this service and responds to reasonable requests in an appropriate timeframe.

Back to top

**Cookies.** A cookie is a small file placed on your computer when you visit a site that can be understood by the site that issued the cookie. We use cookies to monitor how our sites are used and to help personalize your online experience. For example, when you register on our sites, we may store a unique code in a cookie on your computer. The next time you come back to the site from that computer, our servers use the cookie to recognize your device. We can then use the information you provided when you registered, combined with your activities on our sites to provide advertising and offers of interest. 

You can accept or decline cookies. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. To learn more about cookies look at the cookie settings available in your specific web browser.

**Web Beacons.** Web beacons are small bits of code that communicate with third parties and are embedded in web pages, our ads or in emails. We may use web beacons to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited a web page, to understand usage patterns or other third party functionality. We also may include web beacons in e-mails to learn if messages have been opened, acted on, or forwarded. 

You can disable the ability of Web beacons to store cookie information by declining cookies.

**Other Technologies.** Examples of other technologies we may use to provide better service to you follow: 

  * **Web Session Variables.** Information that is passed from one web URL to another as you browse.
  * **Browser plug-ins/add-ons.** Additional web components that may need to be installed to enable certain web features on our sites. You have the option not to install these components.

**Third-Party Advertising.** We may allow third parties, including business partners and ad networks, to display advertising on our sites. Some of these companies may place a cookie on your computer to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. This enables them to understand where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisement and deliver ads that they believe are of interest to you. We do not control these companies’ use of cookies. Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), which offers a single location to opt out of their cookies. Please visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s website at:  
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>

**How we use Cookies, Web Beacons and other Technologies.** We use these technologies to provide you a richer and more personalized consumer experience. We do not store any of your personal information in cookies, web beacons or other technologies on your computer. For more detail see

 _“How We Use This Information.”_

**Interest Based Advertising**

Where legally permitted, you may receive P&G interest-based ads as you interact with websites on the internet. P&G Interest-based ads are advertisements for P&G [_brands_](http://www.pg.com/en_US/brands/index.shtml) or our carefully selected business partners that we hope you find more relevant to your interests. We serve interest based ads according to certain general interest categories that we have inferred based on information such as: 

  * The web pages you view and links you click on P&G websites and other websites you visit.
  * The P&G brand emails you view and links you click in the email.
  * Demographic data.
  * Offline purchase data, which may be combined with your online website activity to create a better profile of your interests. For example, if you purchase diapers at the grocery store, you may receive an ad with a coupon for Pampers.

We have designed our interest based advertising systems to deliver ads to you based only on data that does not personally and directly identify you.

**We respect your privacy.**  
If you don’t want to receive interest-based ads visit the[ _About Ads_](http://www.pg.com/en_US/privacy/en_na/oba_notice.shtml) link on our websites in the United States and Canada, where you can choose to opt out. P&G will honor that choice.

You can also opt out of receiving interest-based ads by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative’s website at:  

[](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp)Back to top

The success of our business depends on your trust, and we do not sell your personal information to marketers outside of P&G. We share your personal information only as described below and within P&G. 

In general, we do not share personal information with marketers outside of P&G unless we have clearly asked for and obtained your explicit consent.

**Third-party service providers.** We rely on third-party service providers to perform a variety of services on our behalf. In so doing, we may need to share your personal information with them. Please note that we provide our service providers with only the personal information they need to perform their services and we require that they protect this information and not use it for any other purpose. 

For example, we may rely on a service provider to: 

  * Fulfill your product and service requests and answer your questions.
  * Host our sites and deliver our email and mobile messages.
  * Mail product samples, contact contest winners, manage payments or take other actions on our behalf.
  * Analyze data, sometimes combined with other sources, to send more targeted communications to you.
  * Conduct research and analyze data to improve our products, services and sites.

**  
In addition, where permitted by law, we may also rely on a service provider to:  
**

  * Combine personal information about you that P&G has collected with personal information about you that our business partner has collected so we can jointly send tailored promotional communications to you. In such instances, our business partner will not have direct access to any information we share about you with the service provider, and only the service provider will be allowed to use the combined set of information to send you joint communications that we hope will be of interest to you. If you prefer not to receive these joint communications, you can always opt out by following the instructions provided in any such communication or through this Privacy Statement as indicated above
  * Perform other services that we request.

We provide these companies with the personal information they need to provide these services on our behalf. We require these companies to protect this personal information and to not use the information for any other purpose. 

**Other situations.** We may disclose your personal information: 

  * If a P&G brand is sold to another company.
  * Where permitted by law, to protect and defend the rights and property of P&G (including enforcing our Terms and Conditions).
  * And when required by law, and/or public authorities.

**Aggregated and non-personal information.** We may share aggregated information that cannot identify you for general business analysis. For example, we may disclose the number of visitors to P&G sites or services. 

Back to top

Some P&G sites enable users to submit their own content for contests, blogs, videos, and other functions. Please remember that any information you disclose becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal, financial or other information in a submission. P&G cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Privacy Statement, the law, or your personal privacy and safety and is not responsible for the results of such postings.

Back to top

We are committed to keeping personal information secure. We have appropriate technical, administrative and physical procedures in place to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration.

We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need. We keep personal information only for a reasonably needed amount of time.

When we provide your personal information to our third party service providers we require those companies to protect the information and to not use the information for any other purpose.

When we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit card number, we use industry standard methods to protect that information.

Back to top

Your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in a country other than the one in which it was provided. This may include the US. When we do so, we transfer the information in compliance with applicable data protection laws. 

We take steps to protect personal information no matter what country it is stored in or transferred to. We have procedures and controls as appropriate to help ensure this.

We adhere to the EU Data Privacy Directive and country data privacy laws, as well as the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program. 

Back to top

We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to participate in and monitor their online activity. 

We do not intend to collect personal information from children under 13 online, except on some sites specifically directed to children. 

When we do collect personal information from children, we do so in compliance with applicable country children’s data protection laws. 

U.S. sites that collect information from children under the age of 13 are covered by a privacy statement that meets the requirements of the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act. [Click here](http://www.beinggirl.com/en_US/pages/privacy.jsp "Klik di sini") to read that Privacy Statement. 

[Click here ](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/privacy_country_list.html "Klik di sini") to find out how to obtain a copy of the information your child has provided P&G, to update the information or instruct us to no longer contact your child

Back to top

If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy, please contact P&G directly. [Click here ](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/contact_us/privacy-central-contact-interactive.html "Click here") to select your country and be linked to the correct address or e-mail address to use, or use the postal address below. Please feel free to use your native language when sending your questions or comments. 

Otherwise, you can contact us at this address  
**P &G Global Privacy Team**  
**1 P &G Plaza**  
**Cincinnati, Ohio 45202 USA**

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy. We cooperate with country data protection authorities if they believe that a privacy problem has occurred.

We participate in the U.S. Council of Better Business Bureau’s (BBB) Accredited Business Program. Further information about this program and its dispute resolution process is available at [www.bbb.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/ "www.bbb.org")

**Privacy Complaints by European Union Citizens:** **  
**  
In compliance with the Safe Harbor Principles, P&G commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact P&G. 

The Procter & Gamble Company has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and EU-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by The Procter & Gamble Company, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints) for more information and to file a complaint.

For more information on how to help protect your computer, your personal information and your family online, visit our Personal Privacy Tips   
<http://www.pg.com/yourprivacy/index.shtml>

Back to top

We will post changes to this Privacy Statement and update the effective date when this Privacy Statement is updated. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Statement, we will notify you by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address you most recently provided us or by posting notice of the changes on this site. 

Last updated: **December 2013**

**December 2013 Update**  
Included a hyperlink in the Privacy Statement to an online program that provides individuals the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of information about their online activities over time and across websites. This hyperlink is also available on webpages in the United States and Canada. 

**2013 update**  
No substantive changes were made to the Privacy Statement. Outdated hyperlinks to third party websites were removed. The “Cookie, Web Beacons, and Other Technologies” section was updated to better reflect consumer control options and remove inaccurate links to web browsers.  
The Country specific information for Mexico was updated to reflect recent guidance on Ley Federal de Protección de Datos Personales en Posesión de los Particulares 

**2011 update**  
The Country Specific Information for France was updated and the Country Specific Information for Mexico was added. 

**2008 Update**  
Clarifies that within P&G, the information you provide to one P&G brand may now be shared within the company across any P&G brand. This change allows us to (1) better tailor our advertising and offers to you and (2) tell you about all the products and services offered by P&G that we think may be of interest to you. 

**2005 update**  
No substantive changes were made to the Privacy Statement. This update was to: clarify and simplify the content to improve readability; remove reference to specific advertising partners; add information about how to manage cookies, and to indicate the addition of a children’s privacy statement for certain U.S. websites. 

**2002 Update**  
No substantive changes were made to the Privacy Statement. This update was to: clarify that a company that purchases a P&G brand may obtain information about consumers who had signed up for that brand; add examples of the types of third parties that P&G may share information with if consumers give us consent, change the name of the advertising partner; and clarify children’s privacy to be in line with local law, and to provide a physical address for our corporate offices. 

Back to top

Country Specific Information

La información y datos que Ud. nos proporcione voluntariamente a través del Sitio Web se incluirán en una base de datos que quedará bajo la responsabilidad de P&G, con el objetivo de proporcionarle un servicio personalizado y a la altura de sus necesidades, mejorando el canal de comunicación con el usuario. Sus datos también podrán utilizarse para elaborar estadísticas y estudios de mercado. Si no desea recibir mensajes, podrá solicitar la cancelación del envío de mensajes de acuerdo con el procedimiento que más adelante se indica.

Se le informa que su registración en el Sitio Web implica que Ud. presta su consentimiento expreso, libre e informado para la inclusión, uso y tratamiento de sus datos personales por P&G. 

P&G realizará el tratamiento de sus datos personales en un todo de acuerdo con su política de privacidad y las disposiciones de la Ley 25.326, sobre Protección de los Datos Personales, adoptando los recaudos técnicos y organizativos necesarios en lo que respecta a la custodia, almacenamiento, conservación y confidencialidad de la información con el fin de evitar su alteración, pérdida, tratamiento o acceso no autorizado. Debido a que ninguna transmisión vía Internet puede garantizar su íntegra seguridad, Jumbo no puede garantizar que la información transmitida a través del Sitio Web se encuentre completamente segura, con lo cual Ud. asume este riesgo, que declara conocer y aceptar. 

Sus datos personales podrán ser compartidos con empresas contratadas por P&G a fin de poder ofrecerle nuestros servicios y cumplir con las presentes Condiciones de Uso, para lo cual Ud. presta su expreso consentimiento y autorización. 

Ud. tiene la facultad de ejercer el derecho de acceso a sus datos personales en forma gratuita a intervalos no inferiores a seis (6) meses, salvo que se acredite un interés legítimo al efecto, conforme lo establecido en el artículo 14, inciso 3 de la Ley 25.326 (Disposición 10/2008, artículo 1°, B.O. 18/09/2008) y a solicitar su actualización, rectificación o supresión de sus datos personales. A tal fin, deberá completar su información en este link [http://pgconsumercare.force.com/PGContactUs?Country=Argentina&lang=es&website=LAsocialmed](http://pgconsumercare.force.com/PGContactUs?Country=Argentina&lang=es&website=LAsocialmed) o comunicarse telefónicamente 0800-999-7625.

Se le hace saber que la Dirección Nacional de Protección de Datos Personales, órgano de control de la ley 25.326, tiene la atribución de atender las denuncias y reclamos que se interpongan con relación al incumplimiento de las normas sobre protección de datos personales. 

Back to top

Conformément à la Loi sur la Protection de la Vie Privée du 8 décembre 1992, vous disposez d'un droit d'accès et de rectification de vos données personnelles. Vous pouvez également vous opposer à leur traitement. Le responsable du traitement de vos données en Belgique est la société Procter & Gamble DCE (Belgium Distribution Division) sprl.

Pour tout renseignement complémentaire, vous pouvez vous adresser à notre service du consommateur en Belgique: **Service du Consommateur, BP 81, 1090 Bruxelles.**

Overeenkomstig de Wet op de Bescherming van de Persoonlijke Levensfeer van 8 december 1992, heeft u het recht tot toegang en tot verbetering van uw persoonlijke gegevens. U kan zich eveneens verzetten tegen het houden van uw persoonlijke gegevens. De verantwoordelijke voor de bewerking van uw gegevens in Belgïe is de venootschap Procter & Gamble DCE (Belgium Distribution Division) bvba.

Wil u meer weten hierover, kan u contact opnemen met onze consumentendienst in Belgïe: **Consumentendienst, BP 81, 1090 Brussel.**

Back to top

Procter & Gamble Inc. complies with Canadian Federal and Provincial privacy laws and regulations including the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act.

Procter & Gamble Inc. will only use your personal information for the purposes intended and as detailed in the Global Privacy Statement unless we have obtained your consent to use it for other purposes.

Residents of Canada are notified that the personal information they provide to Procter & Gamble is stored in the company’s databases outside of Canada including in the United States and may be subject to disclosure to authorized law enforcement or government agencies in response to lawful demand pursuant to the laws of that country.

If you need to contact Procter & Gamble Inc. regarding your personal information, then please write to the following address:

**Consumer Relations**  
**1-800-668-0150**  
**P.O Box 355, Station A**  
**Toronto** **, ON, M5W 1C5** ****

**Email:[privacyfeedbk.im@pg.com](mailto:privacyfeedbk.im@pg.com "mailto:privacyfeedbk.im@pg.com")**

Back to top

Les informations que vous nous communiquez sont utilisées à des fins de prospection et de fidélisation et/ou pour vous faire éventuellement parvenir des informations sur nos produits ou ceux d’autres sociétés. Elles pourront être temporairement transférées hors Union Européenne pour qualification, hébergement.

Vous disposez d’un droit d’accès, de rectification et d’opposition aux informations qui vous concernent. Pour exercer ce droit, contactez :

**Procter & Gamble France SAS  
163/165 quai Aulagnier - 92600 Asnières-sur-Seine  
E-mail : [frconsumers@custhelp.com](mailto:frconsumers@custhelp.com)**

Back to top

Για περισσότερες πληροφορίες σχετικά με το ελληνικό νομικό πλαίσιο, μπορείτε να ανατρέξετε στον ν.2472/1997 και τις αποφάσεις της Αρχής Προστασίας Δεδομένων.

**ΠΡΟΚΤΕΡ & ΓΚΑΜΠΛ ΕΛΛΑΣ ΕΠΕ  
Λ.Συγγρού 165, 17 121 Νέα Σμύρνη  
Υπηρεσία Καταναλωτών: 0800 –23000 (χωρίς χρέωση)**

Back to top

Ai sensi e per gli effetti del D.Lgs. 196/2003 sulla privacy, ti informiamo che, nel caso tu fornisca i tuoi dati navigando all'interno di questo sito, i dati medesimi potranno essere trattati, con mezzi elettronici,direttamente o anche attraverso terzi, per le seguenti finalita'

1\. effettuare ricerche di mercato e sondaggi, anche on-line;  
2\. inviare materiale informativo, pubblicitario, promozionale e/o commerciale, sia per via e-mail che via posta, relativo sia alla Procter & Gamble che ai suoi prodotti;  
3\. effettuare eventuale attivita' di vendita diretta;  
4\. effettuare comunicazioni commerciali interattiva  
5\. partecipare a giochi e concorsi

I dati potranno inoltre essere comunicati a societa' controllate, collegate e/o partecipate dalla The Procter & Gamble Company, o comunque facenti parte del gruppo Procter & Gamble in Italia e/o all'estero (anche paesi extra UE), nonche' a societa' terze che effettuino attivita' di trattamento dati per conto della Procter & Gamble stessa, fermi restando i livelli di sicurezza utilizzati per proteggerli ed i fini per i quali sono trattati.  
In nessun caso i dati saranno ceduti a Societa' terze per fini commerciali diversi da quelli della Procter & Gamble e dei suoi marchi senza il tuo preventivo consenso.  
In relazione al trattamento dei dati, potrai altresi' esercitare in qualunque momento i diritti previsti dall'art. 7 del D. Lgs. 196/2003, rivolgendoti a Procter & Gamble – Viale Giorgio Ribotta 11 – 00144 Roma 

Back to top

개인정보 관리책임자 및 관련부서  
"P&G"는 이용자의 개인정보를 보호하고 개인정보와 관련한 불만을 처리하기 위하여 아래와 같이 관련 부서 및 개인정보관리책임자를 지정하고 있습니다.

<개인 정보 관리 책임자>   
성 명 : 최 병 욱  
전화번호 : 080-023-3333  
E - M A I L : [vmsmile.im@pg.com](mailto:vmsmile.im@pg.com)

<"P&G" 고객센터>  
부 서 : 소비자 상담실   
전화번호 : 080-023-3333(수신자 부담 요금 전화)  
E - M A I L : [vmsmile.im@pg.com](mailto:vmsmile.im@pg.com)  
문의시간: 오전 9시~오후 6시  
토요일, 일요일 및 공휴일은 휴무입니다. 점심시간은 12:00~13:00 입니다.

13\. 개인정보 침해 관련 상담 및 신고  
개인정보침해에 대한 신고, 상담이 필요하신 경우에는 정보통신부 산하 공공기관인 한국정보보호진흥원(KISA)에 개인정보침해신고센터로 문의하시기 바랍니다. 개인정보침해신고센터  
전화 (02) 1336  
URL : [http://www.1336.or.kr](http://www.1336.or.kr/ "http://www.1336.or.kr")

14\. 정책변경에 따른 공지의무  
"P&G" 개인정보취급방침은 2001년 07월 01일에 제정되었으며 법령, 정책 또는 보안기술의 변경에 따라 내용의 추가, 삭제 및 수정이 있을 시에는 변경되는 개인정보취급방침을 시행하기 최소 10일전에  
"P&G" 홈페이지를 통해 변경이유 및 내용 등을 공지하도록 하겠습니다.

개인정보취급방침 버전번호: V2.0  
개인정보보호정책 시행일자 : 2008년 5월 1일  
개인정보보호정책 최종변경일자 : 2008년 4월 21일

Back to top

Con fundamento en los artículos 15 y 16 de la Ley Federal de Protección de Datos Personales en Posesión de los Particulares (en lo sucesivo la “Ley”) hacemos de su conocimiento que Compañía Procter & Gamble México, S. de R.L. de C.V. (en adelante, “P&G México”), con domicilio en Loma Florida No. 32, Col. Lomas de Vistahermosa, Del. Cuajimalpa de Morelos, México, D.F. C.P. 05100, es responsable de recabar sus datos personales, del uso que se les dé a los mismos y de su protección.

Si usted considera que alguna de las finalidades descritas en este apartado no tiene origen o no es necesaria para el tipo de relación que tiene con P&G México puede manifestar su negativa al tratamiento, respecto de dicha finalidad, a través de la dirección electrónica [privacidadpgmex@pg.com](mailto:privacidadpgmex@pg.com) en los siguientes 5 días hábiles. 

**CONTROLES DE SEGURIDAD Y COMUNICACIÓN DE LOS DATOS PERSONALES.**

P&G México y todo su personal reconoce la importancia de un adecuado tratamiento para sus datos personales y, como consecuencia de ello, se han implementado diversos controles y medidas de seguridad que permiten que dichos datos personales conserven su carácter confidencial y previenen tanto un acceso o uso no autorizado como posibles daños, perdidas o alteraciones a los mismos.   
Los datos personales que han sido recabados de usted se compartirán con otras sociedades (nacionales o internacionales) que forman parte del mismo grupo corporativo de P&G México, podrán ser compartidos también con aquellos proveedores que P&G México utilice para la realización de las actividades relacionadas con los fines señalados, o si otra empresa adquiere a P&G México, o si los mismos son necesarios a fin de proteger y defender los derechos y la propiedad de P&G México (inclusive en la aplicación de nuestros Términos y Condiciones) o cuando la ley o las autoridades así lo requieran, requiriendo por tanto de su consentimiento para dicha transferencia en términos de la fracción III del artículo 37 de la “Ley”.

**LIMITACIÓN DE USO O DIVULGACIÓN DE LOS DATOS PERSONALES.**

Si usted no desea recibir nuestros correos de actualización y notificación de servicios o productos, incluyendo cualquier tipo de material publicitario y/o promocional que se relacione con los productos de P&G México deberá enviar un correo electrónico a la dirección [privacidadpgmex@pg.com](mailto:privacidadpgmex@pg.com).

**EJERCICIO DE DERECHOS ARCO Y POSIBLE REVOCACIÓN DEL CONSENTIMIENTO.**

Usted tiene derecho de acceder a los datos personales que P&G México posea en relación a su persona y también tiene derecho a actualizar o rectificar sus datos personales de ser éstos inexactos o incorrectos, a instruirnos su cancelación si considera que el tratamiento que realizamos no cumple con los principios y deberes que le son aplicables y a oponerse al tratamiento de los mismos para fines específicos o por existir causa legítima para ello. 

El ejercicio de los derechos de acceso, rectificación, cancelación y oposición podrá hacerse valer mediante un escrito libre que cumpla con la información y anexos mínimos descritos por el artículo 29 de la “Ley” y que acompañado por copia de su documento de identificación (y, en su caso, del documento de identificación de su representante y el documento que acredite su personalidad) deberá ser presentado ante el Oficial de Privacidad de P&G México, que es la persona designada para atender y dar trámite a cualquier solicitud en el tema de datos personales (mismo que se encuentra ubicado en el domicilio de P&G México) o bien ser enviado a la dirección electrónica [privacidadpgmex@pg.com](mailto:privacidadpgmex@pg.com) siempre que se confirme vía telefónica su correcta recepción. Asimismo, usted puede comunicarse al teléfono 57.24.20.00 de lunes a viernes de las 9:00 am a las 4:00 pm (hora del centro de México).

P&G México le comunicará la determinación adoptada a su solicitud dentro de un plazo máximo de 20 días hábiles contado desde la fecha de presentación de su solicitud (realizándose dicha comunicación a través del correo electrónico que de usted tengamos o al que proporcione con su escrito) y, si su solicitud fuera procedente, se hará efectiva dentro de los 15 días hábiles siguientes a dicha comunicación (destacándose que, en el supuesto del derecho de acceso, se entregarán copias simples de los archivos que contengan sus datos personales).

Usted también puede revocar su consentimiento al tratamiento mediante una solicitud que entregue o envíe a las direcciones antes mencionadas y respecto de la cual recibirá nuestra respuesta dentro de los 15 días siguientes a su recepción. No obstante, es importante tome en cuenta que dicha revocación podrá afectar la relación comercial que exista entre las partes.

**CONSENTIMIENTO AL TRATAMIENTO:** Para efectos de lo dispuesto por el artículo 8 de la “Ley”, y luego de haberse explicado las características y finalidades del tratamiento y transferencia que daremos a sus datos personales, usted consiente expresamente en este acto que P&G México recabe, almacene, maneje, use y comparta sus datos personales con las demás sociedades de su grupo corporativo y los terceros que utilice para el cumplimiento de las finalidades establecidas en el presente Aviso de Privacidad.

Back to top

Overeenkomstig de Wet van 6 juli 2000 houdende regels inzake de bescherming van persoonsgegevens heeft u het recht tot toegang, verbetering en verzet van uw persoonlijke gegevens. De verantwoordelijke voor de bewerking van uw gegevens in Nederland is de venootschap Procter & Gamble Nederland B.V.

Indien u hierover meer informatie wilt, kunt u schrijven naar:  
**Procter & Gamble Nederland B.V.  
T.a.v. Consumentenservice  
Postbus 1345  
3000 BH ROTTERDAM  
email adres: pgconsumentnl.im@pg.com **

Back to top

Os seus dados pessoais serão recolhidos e inseridos pela **PROCTER & GAMBLE PORTUGAL – Produtos de Consumo, Higiene e Saúde, S.A.** (de ora em diante abreviadamente designada por P&G) num ficheiro automatizado para realização de actividades de marketing destinadas a pessoas com o seu perfil de consumo. O preenchimento dos dados é obrigatório. Caso pretenda vir a ter acesso aos seus dados ou deseje que os mesmos sejam rectificados, alterados ou eliminados deverá dirigir-se à P&G, Ed. Álvares Cabral, Quinta da Fonte, 2774-527 Paço de Arcos. Os dados recolhidos poderão ser transmitidos a outras empresas (designadamente, outras sociedades do grupo Procter & Gamble), sedeadas em Portugal ou no estrangeiro, para realização de actividades de marketing. Caso deseje opor-se a tal cedência deverá assinalar este campo [•]. Se não quiser que os seus dados pessoais sejam utilizados para receber outras comunicações de marketing, por favor assinale este campo[B1][B1] [•]. Nos termos legais, a P&G adoptou medidas para assegurar que os dados facultados sejam protegidos contra o acesso ou utilização por terceiros não autorizados. Todavia, a P&G chama a atenção para a existência de um risco residual de acesso não autorizado na internet. Para aceder à nossa "Declaração sobre Privacidade", por favor, 

_clique aqui:_

www.pg.com/privacy/portuguese/privacy_notice.shtml

Back to top

Sus datos serán incorporados a los ficheros de las compañías PROCTER & GAMBLE ESPAÑA, S.A. y ARBORA & AUSONIA, S.L.U. para informarle y pedir su opinión sobre ésta o nuevas ofertas relativas a los productos y servicios de las citadas sociedades y realizar estudios de mercado, a través de cualquier medio, incluso e-mail o SMS, así como para realizar tratamientos con el objeto de adecuar nuestras comunicaciones a su perfil particular. Asimismo, sus datos podrán ser utilizados por las empresas anteriormente indicadas para enviarle información relativa a terceras empresas relacionadas con los sectores de telecomunicaciones, ocio y gran consumo. Si desea acceder a sus datos, rectificarlos, cancelarlos, oponerse a su tratamiento o que los mismos no sean utilizados para ofrecerle información de las empresas anteriormente mencionadas o de terceras empresas, diríjase a PROCTER & GAMBLE ESPAÑA, S.A. (Avda. de Bruselas nº 24 28108 Alcobendas, Madrid) y ARBORA & AUSONIA, S.L.U. (Pg. dels Til.lers, 2-6, 08034 Barcelona). 

_Si no desea recibir mas información nuestra marque X en esta casilla_

Back to top
